{
  "deck_number": "07",
  "topic": "hdfs",
  "card_count": 16,
  "cards": [
    {
      "note_id": 1697393570653,
      "front": "What does GFS stand for?",
      "back": "Google File System",
      "source_lecture": "19-hdfs",
      "original_tags": "lec19"
    },
    {
      "note_id": 1697393593009,
      "front": "What is the Hadoop system similar to GFS?",
      "back": "HDFS (Hadoop File System)",
      "source_lecture": "19-hdfs",
      "original_tags": "lec19"
    },
    {
      "note_id": 1697393629678,
      "front": "What is a Hadoop system similar to Google's BigTable?",
      "back": "HBase",
      "source_lecture": "19-hdfs",
      "original_tags": "lec19"
    },
    {
      "note_id": 1697393687547,
      "front": "What is a distributed analytics system that many people have started using instead of MapReduce?",
      "back": "Spark",
      "source_lecture": "19-hdfs",
      "original_tags": "lec19"
    },
    {
      "note_id": 1697393719734,
      "front": "When Google MapReduce and BigTable were first created, where did they store their data?",
      "back": "GFS",
      "source_lecture": "19-hdfs",
      "original_tags": "lec19"
    },
    {
      "note_id": 1697393759470,
      "front": "What is the technical word for having multiple copies of our data on different systems?",
      "back": "replication",
      "source_lecture": "19-hdfs",
      "original_tags": "lec19"
    },
    {
      "note_id": 1697393786575,
      "front": "What is the technical word for breaking our data (for example, a file) into smaller pieces that are more manageable?",
      "back": "partitioning",
      "source_lecture": "19-hdfs",
      "original_tags": "lec19"
    },
    {
      "note_id": 1697393824565,
      "front": "HDFS has a boss/worker architecture.&nbsp; What are the specific names given to the boss and workers in an HDFS cluster?",
      "back": "boss: NameNode<br>worker: DataNode",
      "source_lecture": "19-hdfs",
      "original_tags": "lec19"
    },
    {
      "note_id": 1697393954782,
      "front": "When a client wants to read an HDFS file, how does it interact with the NameNode and DataNodes?",
      "back": "First it tells the NameNode what it wants to read, and the NameNode responds with information about where the client can find the data.<br><br>Then, the client fetches the data directly from the DataNodes.<br><br>Data does not flow through the NameNode because otherwise having a single NameNode would be a major bottleneck.",
      "source_lecture": "19-hdfs",
      "original_tags": "lec19"
    },
    {
      "note_id": 1697394036715,
      "front": "What are pipelined writes?",
      "back": "If a client wants to write 3 replicas of a block to DataNodes DN1, DN2, and DN3, it does not send the data directly to each of them.<br><br>Instead, it sends the data to DN1, which forwards to DN2, which forwards to DN3.<br><br>This prevents any one computer from having too much work (most importantly, the client isn't doing all the work, because the client may be a weaker machine than the servers).",
      "source_lecture": "19-hdfs",
      "original_tags": "lec19"
    },
    {
      "note_id": 1697394103593,
      "front": "If you write 1 MB to a triply replicated file, how much disk I/O does that generate?&nbsp; What if you read 1 MB from a triply replicated file?",
      "back": "Write: 3 MB (need a copy on each machine, for safety)<br>Read: 1 MB (the three machines have identical data, so there is no point in requesting it from more than one)",
      "source_lecture": "19-hdfs",
      "original_tags": "lec19"
    },
    {
      "note_id": 1697466904426,
      "front": "How do you format an HDFS NameNode?",
      "back": "<div>hdfs namenode -format</div>",
      "source_lecture": "19-hdfs",
      "original_tags": "lec19"
    },
    {
      "note_id": 1697466932552,
      "front": "How do you start running an HDFS NameNode with hostname \"main\" and port 9000?",
      "back": "<div>hdfs namenode --fs hdfs://main:9000</div>",
      "source_lecture": "19-hdfs",
      "original_tags": "lec19"
    },
    {
      "note_id": 1697466961705,
      "front": "How can you get an HDFS cluster report for hdfs://main:9000/?",
      "back": "<div>hdfs dfsadmin -fs hdfs://main:9000/ -report</div>",
      "source_lecture": "19-hdfs",
      "original_tags": "lec19"
    },
    {
      "note_id": 1697466995208,
      "front": "How can you start a DataNode and connect it to a NameNode with hostname \"main\" on port 9000?",
      "back": "hdfs datanode -fs hdfs://main:9000",
      "source_lecture": "19-hdfs",
      "original_tags": "lec19"
    },
    {
      "note_id": 1697467054692,
      "front": "If you want to use commands like mkdir, cp, ls, cat, and du on HDFS, how do you do it?",
      "back": "hdfs dfs -COMMAND ARGS<br><br>For example, to run \"ls\" on the \"data\" directory:<br><div>hdfs dfs -ls hdfs://main:9000/data/</div>",
      "source_lecture": "19-hdfs",
      "original_tags": "lec19"
    }
  ]
}